## Marcus Madison

mimadison23@gmail.com ■212-671-2702 ■ New York, NY

■LinkedIn ■ Tableau ■ Github ■ Portfolio Website

A Data Engineer with a specific interest in machine learning and AI, I enjoy learning new things in environments conducive to producing results and that have similar goals in mind. I am well versed in data manipulation and have experience with NLP and LLMs.

**Technical Skills:** SQL, R, Python, Tableau, Google Analytics, SwiftUI, AWS(Athena), Agile/ Waterfall/ Lean Six Sigma methodologies, Unix, Redash, APIs, HTML, Notion

Certifications: Google Data Analytics Certificate, Google Project Management Certificate, New York State Security License

#### **Experience**

#### **Consulting/Personal Projects & Learning**

Aug 2023 - Present

Google Password Analytics/ Generator(Sheets, Python, Pytorch)

Jan 2024

- Collected passwords using Google's Password Manager to derive metrics about their length, starting characters, frequency of characters, and general entropy of the string. Pytorch was then used to develop a password generator using the passwords collected as well as the entropy that was derived including suggesting passwords with both normal and special characters.

## **Microsoft Azure Databricks for Data Engineering**

Present

- Learning about ETL processes while interacting with Azure through a databricks notebook, exposing myself to SparkSQL, Pyspark, and a bit of scala. This course also is familiarizing me with general database security measures as well as the import of data through various means whether they be csv, tsc, or come from the Spark API itself.

Mutiny

Data Engineering Intern (PrestoSQL, Python, Google Analytics, AWS, Postman)

Remote, NY May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Streamlined access to customer information, improving project efficiency and effectiveness across teams reducing the time to create reports for the BDR team by 50%.
- Updated metrics to now utilize a refined four-week historical data analysis approach for improved accuracy and predictive capability, allowing for more insight into what consumers are using more and how often they launch experiences.
- Enriched customer data by applying Clearbit's API to update internal records and compile data on potential leads for the Sales team ensuring that information on our User Funnel was up to date and accurate.
- Developed datasets customized for finance, customer experience, growth, and other teams using Presto to create pipelines and dashboards on Redash

## **BEST Gardaworld**

Brooklyn, NY

#### Guest Service Specialist/ Security

Nov 2021- Dec 2022

- Spearheaded the role of a front-line ambassador at Barclays Center, dedicated to crafting exceptional guest experiences for events ranging from 15,000 to 19,000 people..
- Welcomed and provided assistance to guests, corporate executives, team officials, players, and performers, facilitating their seamless navigation through the venue.
- Progressed to the position of Licensed Security Officer, reflecting my commitment to enhancing guest experiences and ensuring their safety at Barclays Center.

# Open Avenues(Tamr)

Remote, NY

## Data Science Intern (Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Google Analytics)

June 2022 -Aug 2022

- Utilized Pandas, Numpy, and other Python packages for efficient data manipulation to improve data quality and accessibility of medical professional datasets, collectively consisting of over 4 million data entries.
- Built a <u>dataset</u> simplifying identification of doctors with clinical trial experience to be used for planning in future trials by organizations employing Tamr's services.

#### Education

Fullstack Academy (PostgreSQL, MySQL, Python, Tableau, Powerpoint)
Jan 2023 - May 2023

New York, NY

TTP DATA Accelerator Course

Selected by NYC's Tech Talent Pipeline as 1 of 25 participants out of approximately 700 applicants.

## CUNY Queens College (Statistics, SPSS, A/B Testing) Aug 2018 - May 2024

Queens, NY In Progress

BA in Economics: Engaged in courses based on mathematics, statistics, and life sciences. 31 credits left.